<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>academic on Guillaume Corbisier</title>
    <link>/tags/academic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in academic on Guillaume Corbisier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Guillaume Corbisier (license [CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/))</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Albinism in human society and animal society ?</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-11-albinism-what-is-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-11-11-albinism-what-is-this/</guid>
      <description>Albino in human and animals society,research about it and some devellopement
What is albinism ? It ‘s a hereditary anomaly who cause a problem in pigmentation and a white aspect because the individu have lost his production in melanine. The anomaly touch reptil, birds, amphibian, mamal, fish and plant and make completely the albino white even if he have a normal number of melanocytes or pigments cell.
But that’s not all the albino is very affected by the light, the UV present in the light can cause burned an cancer of the skin normal people are not touched with the protection of the melanocyte and the constant reparation of the ADN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color blindness</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Genetic Color blindness is a mutation that can cause ,like the name says, a malformation of the iris who is involve in colour perception. This anomaly is a modification on the X chromosm who are hedetary. The mutation is gived to the child like a typical recesive ill on the X chromosm. A male mutant can&#39;t give is anomaly to his son because he give Y chromosm to him. And a female affected by the ill will give it to his son 100% chance of time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>