<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guillaume Corbisier on Guillaume Corbisier</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guillaume Corbisier on Guillaume Corbisier</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Guillaume Corbisier (license [CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/))</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My project</title>
      <link>/project/example-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/example-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here I describe my project using Markdown formatting...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Herbarium</title>
      <link>/project/2018-10-01-herbarium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/2018-10-01-herbarium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here I describe my project using Markdown formatting...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./project/2018-10-01-herbarium_files/Plants.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Albinism in human society and animal society ?</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-11-albinism-what-is-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-11-11-albinism-what-is-this/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Albino in human and animals society,research about it and some devellopement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-albinism&#34;&gt;What is albinism ?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It ‘s a hereditary anomaly who cause a problem in pigmentation and a white aspect because the individu have lost his production in melanine.
The anomaly touch reptil, birds, amphibian, mamal, fish and plant and make completely the albino white even if he have a normal number of  melanocytes or pigments cell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not all the albino is very affected by the light, the UV present in the light can cause burned an cancer of the skin normal people are not touched with the protection of the melanocyte and the constant reparation of the ADN.Albino have a déoloration of the iris too and a deformation of the retina,the gene responable of albinism is a recesif gene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;physiologic-point&#34;&gt;Physiologic point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pigmentation is controled by two type of cell : keratynocyte who stock melanine and melanococyte who product it.
Melanocytes make melanine in organites and melanosome are transfert in keratinocytes who are transported to the surface of the epiderm.For black people melanosme are isolated but witha high density at the opposite of the other.
3 type of melanocyte exist in the epiderm, eye and hair, These three types is managed by different gene and mutation can cause modification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;albino-in-society&#34;&gt;Albino in society&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people ar affected by albinism in human society it can cause problem of racism. In amerindian population albino are treated like savior and chief or are use for sacrifice, this big difference is caused by the difference of religion between all tribs.In africa albino are persecuted, murdered in some contry because they think albino have organ that can heal ill obsously that&#39;s not true but some people are specialised in creation of potion withh albino organ. People change and now judgement exist against persecutor but no &amp;quot;potion&amp;quot; maker were been judge . Albinism is more present in Africa but all population are affected.Human have made a law against the hunt of albino animal in some country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;desavantage-of-the-albino-for-animal&#34;&gt;Desavantage of the albino for animal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This desavantages cause a selection important in the animal world the white fur cause reject in the group (animal don’t like other different animal) so reproduction is very difficult and this is hard to survive lonely for many species of animal but albino is sometimes less hunt by the predator because they think the albino is ill and not really good to eat but with white fur the albino don’t have any cameo and are more easily catchable in a normal biome. Advandages and incoveniants are not very balanced and the problem of rejection, cameo and cancer with the contact of the light on their skin make a big selection. This difference can be an advantages in a specific zone ? Any results can confirm this hypothesis i hope find one day some information about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Color blindness</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;genomic&#34;&gt;Genomic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Color blindness is a mutation that can cause ,like the name says, a malformation of the iris who is involve in colour perception. This anomaly is a modification on the X chromosm who are hedetary. The mutation is gived to the child like a typical recesive ill on the X chromosm. A male mutant can&#39;t give is anomaly to his son because he give Y chromosm to him. And a female affected by the ill will give it to his son 100% chance of time.Female people have less chance to be colorblind because they have 2 X chromosm and the mutation is recessive so all the parents need to carry the mutant X chromosm to have a colorblind daughter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;detection&#34;&gt;Detection&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isharah test: it&#39;s a test with many panel of different color and number in this panel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Holmgren test: colorblind people have to combinate theard of wheel on a grey background&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nagel anormaloscope: two circle of color assembled to form one other, the colorblind people have to ajust the circle to make them look like a picture and can add blue,red or green to make it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fansworth test: a test with 15 or 85 token with color on them the patient have to classified the token gradualy by using the variance of colour.The classication have to begin with blue and have to go to red.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;type-of-colorblindness&#34;&gt;Type of colorblindness&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It exist three light and one heavy type of colorblidness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acromatopsy: can not seen any color.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deuteranopian: people who cant see green.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protanopian: people who cant see red.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tritanopian: people who cant blue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All mutation are caused by a lost of color receptor in the eye.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
